Hey everyone, today's DeFi drop features
Alex, the CEO and founder of Fensory,
the super app for crypto wealth.
Welcome, Alex. It's great to have you on
finally.
>> Thank you so much, Ed.
>> Cool. And also, I believe you're
chatting with John, our BD at portals as
well, aren't you? for integration with
>> that's cool.
>> Amazing team. Amazing team. Amazing
solution.
>> Thank you. Yeah, we looking forward to
that kicking off.
>> Anyway, yeah, it's great to have you on.
I don't want to hang around with a small
talk because we've been doing that
before we hit record. But what we've
left aside, which I still haven't got,
is all your information about yourself
and what your background is and how you
actually started fencery and why. So
perhaps you can give us a bit of those
details and as well the problem that
you're trying to solve with fencery.
>> For sure. For sure. Look, I mean for the
past um well four years I've been
heavily heavily invested in in
cryptonative capital markets. Um I
previously led BD and sales globally for
a agency lender based in Zurich called
Celeste. Um worked with around 150 uh
cryptonnative institutions. At core the
original concept was to build you know
effective money markets um for
institutional counterparties and then
post FTX um realization hit that that
doesn't necessarily work in a needless
fashion given that we're looking at a
very nent ecosystem with no existing
credit risk ratings um let alone audited
financials at that point. So we started
to provide agency services, whlo
services to large LPs in the space. Um
typically you know those LPs um would
hold a couple hundred million worth of
crypto um primarily Bitcoin and stable
coins natively on balance sheet and
we're looking for risk adjusted returns.
So um over the course of I'd say uh two
years um we've you know worked with
those institutions on a day-to-day basis
analyzed their mandate or goals um built
treasury frameworks risk frameworks um
source the counterparties help them to
deploy um you know unsecure credit
secure credit structure credit we've
built um intraday credit facilities you
know to manage duration risk so we were
funding a lot of DTF create transaction
options we deployed into hedge funds and
and all of this at scale. So my my book
of clients over the course um of my well
um you know stint at Celeste um you know
we've deployed about a billion dollars
worth of Bitcoin and stable coins. So
the topic of I'd say risk adjusted inind
returns was a top of my mind for um a
while. left the company um in October of
2024,
wanted to take a brever, spend some time
with the kids, and what really happened
specifically post election was that a
lot of my old clients, both issuers and
LPs, uh kept bringing me um simple sort
of simple and and I'd say more complex
uh questions, but it sort of I I guess
like the common denominator was, hey,
we're seeing solution X and Y, but we
don't necessarily know how to bend
market. Hey, uh, you know, Hedge Fund XY
just pitched us a Bitcoin native, you
know, strategy. How do they compare?
And, um, to me, I'd say Discovery to,
you know, to that point in time wasn't
necessarily top of mind because we had a
reputation in a market um, that we could
deploy at scale. So most of the deals
that we would see we would get inbound
um because again um we've worked with
150 institutions whenever there was
something interesting in a market we
were one of the first you would call um
but I realized in that very moment that
if you take away that sort of super
specialized intermediary then LPS are
entirely left on their own especially if
maybe you aren't part of that you know
mystic cycle of couple hundred
institutions that work in crypto. And so
it triggered um a a bit of a a research
exercise in me where I wanted to better
understand if I have say Google, right?
Um and my maybe limited personal
networks, how I actually discover
solutions that fit into my mandate. Long
story short, came to the conclusion very
very hard. So got myself a Replet Pro,
built a functional pilot version um with
the idea in mind that we could
effectively index the global investments
opportunities landscape and um went back
to my old clients, got the Southside on
board, a number of you know great great
issuers, got 60 allocators on board, ran
a pilot for about 4 months and then to
my surprising um inbound uh came in um
people started calling wanted to get on
to the application and then in about was
probably July um one of the hedge funds
turned around and said hey can we become
a premium subscriber
um one we're interested in getting
additional visibility but second we'd be
very keen on getting a better
understanding of user intent for
underlying product design at that point
I had no terms of and conditions I had
no entity and so I was like well it's
about time we turn this into a proper
business and that effectively is the
origin story of Fenry. What we are doing
at Fenzer is we are aggregating the
global investment universe um
addressable solutions that are
cryptodenominated
with the sole intent to effectively
become the single sign on the super app
for crypto wealth that allows um
professional I'd say advanced retail all
the way to smaller institutions that you
know have crypto balance sheet interact
with this ecosystem in a mindful
Wow, thanks for that that background and
what Fensory is all about. That's very
very helpful. You support like SMAs, D5
walls, CD5, RWA, all these structured
products and all in one neutral
non-custodial platform which is pretty
cool. And also I love that you properly
bootstrapped this at the beginning. you
did the good thing and and and went out
there and found the demand, found the
you know, found a real solution to a
real problem and then you found yourself
in that position of, oh my gosh, we we
better we better create a company.
>> Uh it's a third company I'm building.
I'm building 0ero to one. Um I'm a big
believer in lean startup and I guess you
know AI is allowing us to prototype
quickly and not prototype as in the old
days you know spinning up a Figma
prototype at the very end of the day and
I'm not an engineer um obviously we have
a CTO today but I'm not an engineer but
at the end of the of of the pilot
exercise that I had about 16 APIs
integrated with actual you know chron
jobs realtime data and I think it's well
it's it's the beauty of AI I um you know
to be in a position to validate ideas
and concepts quickly. Um although I do
have to say that you know looking at the
current crypto Twitter X uh timeline um
I think expectations are still a little
bit off at times
>> um as to how far AI is getting you.
>> Um but that's a that's a topic for
another day I guess.
>> Okay. And uh what what was behind the
switch? you you had a different brand
when you launched initially. Uh Amber
Markets, how come you switched? Was it
just an instinctive thing?
>> Sorry guys, we had a bit of a technical
issue there. So, we've had a bit of a
break, but we're back now. I'll go back
to where we were. Alex was telling us
about the rebrand which they've just
done. Fencery. It was Amber Markets
initially rebranded to Fencory. But
there's also another point I'd love Alex
to touch on as well, which is the
positioning as an operating system for
crypto capital markets. So, what
triggered the pivot? And let's chat a
bit more about the uh the operating
system.
>> It's it's somewhat of a boring story. Um
when I started um the this the initial
pilot phase I had um the understanding
that this is a pilot that we will scrap
the version that I'm currently building
um and that is for the sole purpose of
you know validating our core hypothesis.
Amber markets I had laying around in my
GoDaddy account um opted in for Amber
Markets. Um at the same time, crypto has
an oversaturation of of amber brands. Um
and so when we conclude a pilot, we
effectively sat down um ideiated around
naming and and the ultimate goal um
which is mass adoption um making sure
that crypto becomes broadly speaking
more accessible and and somewhat you
know derdifying the space. Hence, it was
important for us that we opt in for a
brand that feels more like fintech less
than deep tech. And I was of the opinion
that a com brand that is memorable would
would make sense. Hence, fenry.com.
Now for the operating side, the
operating system side, we effectively
are currently in what I would call the
super app phase which means that we are
building this the single sign on
terminal that you know hopefully in a
few months from now we'll be in a
position where users don't have a ne
necessity to ever leave the platform. So
that is our I'd say front-end journey.
But while we are rolling this out and
while we are getting adoption
um on onto the platform, this really
means that you know at the core we are
building a massive liquidity
um aggregator and ecosystem.
And so I think the end game for us is is
truly to be the operating system where
not only um users effectively do
discovery but where liquidity broadly
speaking also resides
>> that that's really cool and you're
starting with BTC and stable coins
initially.
>> So so we do cover everything but and I
think you know I probably you've picked
up the Bitcoin and stable coin part from
the website. I think it has a bit of an
SEO purpose there. Um, generally
speaking, I think people overestimate
the I'd say
transactional
um dominance of altcoins when it comes
to investment products and solutions.
>> In reality, if you look at pure
notionals, then it's it's stable coins,
it's Bitcoin, ETH, and Solana. And so at
the very end of the day, we are
primarily targeting um investors that do
hold Bitcoin, stable coins, and then
again naive. Um but naturally speaking,
we cover um pretty much everything that
that's relevant out there um and
addressable.
>> Let's take a look at the workflow then.
Um if you could walk us through that.
Let's say I arrived with a mandate um
duration, jurisdiction, liquidity,
needs, risk, limits, all of that. How
does fence take me from discovery to
short list due diligence?
>> Right. I I think there is a there is a a
number of routes that you could possibly
take. So we do support um if somebody is
hugely into clicking um they can
obviously do this on the terminal. Um I
think ultimately and this is where we
take a um I'd say a very different
approach than a lot of the platforms out
there and and I have a very strong
belief there. So if I'm in Trafi um and
I'm trying um as an issuer selling
something to a Trafy firm or if I'm
representing a Traty LP then the way it
effectively works is you have a
portfolio and within the portfolio
you have different mandates. So looking
at private credit, the private credit
mandate could be um we are investing
into receivables financing with
underlying insurance 5 years track
record on the issuer um at say 9 to 15%
peranom. The same thing works for bonds
right we do invest into investment grade
bonds in the North American region
industries XYC's that that's effectively
how you would use Bloomberg today. Now
that doesn't work in crypto at all. And
so what we are introducing from launch
is effectively mandatebased views which
means before you actually do start the
terminal you will effectively choose and
pick your mandate and on the back of
that specific mandate you get a
completely catered view of the
opportunity set. For certain ICPS more
on the retail and the savings end you
will also get a completely catered UI
that is effectively digestible. So if
you think about a retail allocator
then um at the end of the day your
mandate is to invest into products that
have relatively favorable liquidity um
high liquidity um ideally research at
the stations you know existing risk
ratings audits and so we would
effectively I wouldn't say we're not a
curator but on the back of your mandate
we curate an initial set of opport
opportunities that effectively be deemed
favorable for you. Same thing on a
family office, right? A family office
that has a mandate to invest into
products that are permissioned only and
that have a minimum assigned rating, you
should be in a position to effectively
find products that fit your mandate. Now
obviously again if you want to get the
full opportunity set you will be in a
position to get the full opportunity set
but the mandates are terribly in and
extremely important to improve the UI or
better say the the UX um for for
allocators that are entering the space.
And then I think third we do support
natural language search
um which we think is extremely
beneficial. So think about a query um
show me five curated vaults um with
delta neutral underlying that have a
inbuilt insurance policy for smart
contract risks. Right? So the the issue
um from my perspective also speaking to
a lot of users and institutions is that
it is extremely hard to navigate and
filter for relevance in this market. And
so either you're completely lost
navigating different portals and and
websites um or you effectively again
have inbound requests or or pitches um
and end up you know favoring the loudest
solutions over the best solutions.
>> I'm just on on the platform now playing
with the with the little demo that you
have on the on the hero section of your
homepage. I was playing with it a bit
last week as well when I was prepping
for this. Um it's just super cool. It's
super slick. so easy. There's so much
going on under the hood and I guess it's
just the beginning and you've got a lot
more to come. I just click here like top
salon products, find products, bam, I'm
hit with like five great great research
tools, right? Um and then I can click
here, I can go analyze with AI and I'm
in and and then I can start talking to
the AI about this particular position
and the strategy.
>> It's fantastic.
It's just it's great. It serves a great
point. But um I was going to ask him
something else while I'm on this topic
and following on from what you just
said. markets are like super fragmented
and yeah there's no shared standard
let's say and you're building benchmarks
across
>> risk and performance and liquidity
>> but how do you define risk consistently
then across say a D5 vault versus a CDI
product versus a fund
>> right I I think um and it's it's a bit
of a delicate topic that you know we're
having discussions internally frequently
at the very end of the day we have to
make sure that we remain neutral control
at core. So we should never be you know
in favor of product A versus product B.
Now what we do which I think is
tremendously important as well is we
work with the existing third-party
credit risk rating agencies. Um that is
two folds interesting. One is it allows
you to effectively query specifically
for um risk rated products while we
remain neutral at core. Also I have a
core belief that you know risk ratings
in itself is a extremely complex task.
So I don't think that a platform that
has the intent of providing you know
broad access to a to solutions in the
ecosystem h has the capabilities to do
the ratings itself. Um but second is um
it um
I think it it it's the right way going
about the super approach which is we
want to we want to unify the ecosystem.
Um we take a very collaborative
approach. Um there are extremely good
companies out there that unfortunately
do struggle with you know broader
distribution
and so
our mode at the very end of the day
again is to be the single sign on the
platform that you never leave it's not
necessarily building IP around risk
ratings and so we heavily utilize and
rely on amazing companies that have
built amazing infrastructure including
portals right
>> and Those partnerships have been
cemented in your previous career as
well. I guess you're bringing through a
huge amount of experience into fencery.
You know, this is your third startup. I
guess you've worked with all these big
players before. So, there's huge trust
there. There's track record. Also, I'm
checking again on my little search here
that I've done. I've it's come up with
four prompts. You know, I've got these I
can just click them. I don't even need
to type. What drives the yield in this
product? What are the liquidity
constraints? How's the performance
changed recently? And the final one here
which I can just click on which is what
are the primary risk factors right so so
you're addressing that issue for for
every strategy every position for the
user to do dy
>> and I do have to say that it is quite
literally a preview um of course if and
when we launch in in March um users will
get you know access to the full
opportunity set um the AIS effectively
will be consuming metadata from third
party risk rating agencies they are
going to be consuming data from um
amazing providers such as accountable on
on the reserve at the station end um we
are looking at more complex modeling um
whether that's Monte Carlo simulations
on a on a per product level um obviously
the AI is going to be integrated into
portfolio so it's going to be in a
position to effectively optimize
portfolio send you notifications if you
know you've invested into Athena you
want to get notified them when when
Aphina depexs you want to set automated
liquidation triggers if Athena depexs
you know X standard deviation points.
Um, yeah, we we we're early in the
journey.
>> Super early. But you're also not an
issuer or a custodian. You're you're
aggregating from trusted sources like
we've like we've just mentioned and
standardizing. But what are your rules
like um what gets listed, what gets
flagged, what gets excluded,
>> right? Um we right now are taking a very
simplistic approach um at least for the
sort of early launch um process. So we
heavily rely effectively on um audits
and and and third party attestations um
for I'd say the approval process of
products. Um we do um already exclude
I'd say products that currently show um
an anomaly. um example product that
typically yields 8% spikes to 100% we
would automatically delist it from the
venue and then also for the time being
we are only listing products that have
minimum TBL we will over the next couple
of months um build a fairly
sophisticated
um risk engine that is ultimately going
to be feeding in into the mandates.
Again, we take an approach where we
believe there is no one-sizefits-all.
And so, at the very end of the day,
whether a product is going to be
showcased really depends on the ICP and
your corresponding mandate. If you
identify as a cryptogen, you might
absolutely love those outlier
situations. If it's a retail um you know
retail participant or a family office um
it's going to be way way more stringent.
>> And those family offices are they as
sort of as big as you'll go?
>> You mean in terms of um aumum as big as
they go?
>> Yeah.
>> Right. So we currently when when we are
pushing to market which is in a few
weeks um we take 100% we take a 100% PLG
approach. So we don't necessarily offer
a institutional
um a institutional only package if you
will. Um we are working with family
offices and and and larger allocators um
trying to figure out the best way to
produce a infrastructure that is
transactionable great for them. Now, I
think in reality and and that is a bit
of a a trap in crypto, a lot of founders
overestimate
how easy it will be um or you know to
work with larger institutions. In
reality, a lot of the larger
institutions in in digital assets um
they typically um either build in-house
solutions or rely heavily on third party
advisers and managers and curators. Um
so I think for us it's it's yet to be
seen to what extent we are going to be
structuring
um packages and and offers specifically
for family offices. What we've seen
though is that um from a data
standpoint, so I was more referring to
the actual actual uh transactional life
cycle. From a data standpoint, a lot of
the family offices that have so far used
um terminals such as Misari, um the the
requirements have changed, right? family
offices. Back in the day, if if you'd
look at somebody that is in charge of
crypto at a family office, his typical
day-to-day request by clients would be,
"Hey, uh, can you explain me Dogecoin?"
And so they would use Misari, for
example, to inform themselves about
certain coins. Now, reality speaking,
you get chat GPT and and there's sort of
broader access to, you know, metadata
around individual coins. So the more
common request family offices are
getting now from their clients is, hey,
I do hold, you know, x amount of
bitcoin, how can I deploy those bitcoins
into strategies? You know, is there a
way for me to offset some of the custody
costs, some of the tax burden? And so
people in charge of family offices, they
are effectively now tasked with finding
addressable capital markets um products.
And here we see um a huge demand from
family offices specifically
um looking at at not only uh CD5 or
permission D5 facilities but but also at
at um RWAS and and benchmarking RWAS.
>> You're you're purely on productled
growth I'd say and and retail or smaller
allocators for the time being. Big
bigish smaller allocators let's say for
the time being. Um, back on the on the
product side, you're previewing these AI
search or analytic agents that I've just
been talking about here that answer
these natural language queries.
>> What kinds of questions does it answer
best today? I know it's super early. I I
get it super early. Um, and where would
you in the future or where do you
intentionally force humans to do manual
due diligence because I guess you have
to force some of that back on them.
>> Exactly. Yeah, I think um so I think
where where I personally feel um
usability is is going to be great is is
actually finding products because again
uh there's thousands of products there's
an individual mandate and it's extremely
hard to find the products that actually
fit your requirements on current
systems. So I think natural language
search um is something that we focus on
um improving the outputs improving the
granularity
um improving sort of the scope of the
queries to include you know certain risk
metrics volatility metrics etc. Then I
think second um nobody should be making
a full-on investment decision when using
a analytics agent. But in reality
it let's take a simple example. There is
an insurance policy available for a
specific product or there is a smart
contract audit you know available for a
for a certain product.
I think where this is going to be most
helpful is for people to effectively get
summaries and get individual insights
out of the sort of ocean of metadata
available per individual product. So if
you think a um issuing a insurance
policy for the A app, how do you even
figure out for what it exactly it
covers, right? It sounds great 250k
million, right? Um per user, but if it
only ever covers for say smart
contracts, then it doesn't necessarily
resolve the concerns that you have with
a specific product. And so the way I
would want to see it is it being
effectively your own personal um advisor
and researcher if you will. Um and it
should be in a position to either give
you a simplified understanding of what
you look at or if you have a more
complex requirement
getting to the key and core findings
quicker. And by quicker, I mean going
from 5 hours of reading to 2 minutes.
>> That's amazing. Like a contextual
explainer that surfaces these critical
details without overwhelming the user,
but also putting the ball back in their
court. Man, it's scary where we're going
right now. Hey, the capabilities of this
technology, but it's also cool. It's
really cool, and I think we're going to
see a lot of good come from it. you
know, it's um and and to me personally,
it's it's like an an ongoing thought um
that I think will come true. We're
early, you know, we're taking a lean
approach. Ultimately, the market will
tell us what we should be building. I
don't
I I don't exclude an option for us as
fans in a year two years from now where
the primary experience is effectively
you having a conversation with an with a
voice agent and the voice agent
effectively providing a you know ready
to deploy portfolio. And so we're going
from a terminal with millions of data
points to an experience at least used,
you know, used by most user that again
is effectively a chat window and a
output that is transactionable.
>> It's still going to remain that that
structure. So we can uh we can still
build around that structure. Let's say I
do want to touch a bit more on the moat
because when amazing products like yours
pop up, so do others. Right now from a
builder standpoint I think you know our
mo is that effectively we're not issuing
products um we are extremely
collaborative um we are extremely fast
moving with a very lean team um of
highly experienced people now if you ask
me what is your mode um I I'd flip it
and I would say if in 12 months I go on
Reddit I go on on X and people are
effectively talking about fens
and they are saying I don't actually
ever leave Fenzer then I'm going to be
extremely proud and I think that
ultimately is going to be our mode which
is that it's a one-stop shop you don't
have to ever you don't have to ever
leave I had this discussion just you
know um a few days ago um we will be
covering RWAS
um and so the question really is well
how do you roll out a RWA a platform,
right? And my argument is that at the
very end of the day for us, it is
worthwhile to double down and push
tremendously if we have secondary
liquidity because that closes the loop.
As long as in crypto we're building
systems that aren't closed loop, if you
will, that don't cover the full life
cycle, churn is always going to be high.
And so at the very end of the day, what
I'm trying to achieve here is build
something that is comparable to Robin
Hood or Interactive Brokers or Schwab
where I with my US dollar wealth can
sign on and I don't ever have to leave,
right? I might use a ticker on the side.
I might read some news, but from a
transactional uh transactional uh life
cycle standpoint, there's no necessity
for me to ever move away because I can
buy, I can analyze, I can manage my
portfolio, and I can uh I can sell the
assets, I get notifications in there,
and I would argue that is that is our
mode.
>> Would you ever allow Fenceree to be
integrated on other platforms or would
you want users just landing on Fenceree
and building that household wealth
brand? I I think for us we want to focus
on distribution um and and and and
general usability. So um I don't
necessarily want to build an API
business. Um and again like
>> we love working with portals.
>> You know it's not a market that we
necessarily want to be focusing on. Um
now what we've seen is a a a interest
from advisors and subadvisors that
actually um have family office clients
for example or a financial institution
that want to get their clients access to
those products right um we see an
opportunity for us effectively becoming
um a white label um a single sign on
solution um within a B2B to C B2B model.
So that that's that's definitely
something that we will will be looking
at um and where we have active
conversations with institutions.
>> That's really cool.
>> Right, Alex, I've enjoyed talking with
you. We're certainly going to enjoy our
relationship working with you guys as
well when that kicks off soon. We always
end these podcasts with one question,
which is a bit of a game. It was quite
funny doing it in 2025 because 1010
happened which wasn't funny and then
November 27 or whatever it was happened
20th I can't remember. Um and the
question is
today D5 TVL sits at around 120 billion
as per D5 Lama. What do you predict this
number will be on the 21st of June 2026?
Okay, that's one. And also the 31st of
December, 2026, right? So, we're going
by the solstice this time, the summer
solstice. It will be the first and then
and New Year's Eve.
>> Okay. So, you're asking the 21st of
June, which um by coincidence is my
birthday. And then you want to hear my
prediction for end of year.
>> Exactly.
>> So, I think in June I think we've
recovered to peak of 2025. Um I don't I
don't know the number top of my mind. Um
but I think we've probably lost about
25%ish
just top of my mind since peak 25. So I
think by summer we have recovered and
then I think by end of year next year
it's a good question. I think we will
probably from peak of 2025
see an additional
probably 25 to 50% increase. I do think
uh summer onwards is going to be
extremely interesting.
>> So 21st of June you're saying around I
think it was a 173 billion or 174
billion I think was peak 2025. So we'll
pick a number. You can pick a number.
174 maybe.
>> Yeah. I I'd say I'd say
172.
>> 172.
>> And then And then I guess by end of year
we're probably going to be in the
215ish.
>> 215. Right. You're down. You're in the
game.
Wow. That would be a great birthday
present, wouldn't it? Unlimited points
from portals on the 21st of June if you
get this.
>> We'd love that. We'd love that.
Nice one. Uh, Alex, it's been great
chatting. We'll chat a lot more in the
future and we'll get you back on when
when you're all launched and running and
growing.
>> Would love that. Thanks so much, Ed.
>> Cool. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you and cheers. Thanks.